<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<speak version="1.0" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2001/10/synthesis" xml:lang="en-US">
  <voice name="Microsoft Zira Desktop">
    <prosody rate="100%" volume="100">
      Most business A I tells an owner how to grow. Risk Sovereignty asks a harder question: when the world stops cooperating, what breaks first—and which move preserves the right to choose again tomorrow?
      <break time="500ms"/>

      This company appears profitable before stress. But delayed collections, a partial debt call, and inventory impairment consume more cash than it holds. The first failure is cash—not because it is the most dramatic risk, but because it is the weakest constraint.
      <break time="4000ms"/>

      The numbers are not generated by A I. Business facts and stress assumptions stay visible and editable. A deterministic engine recalculates stressed revenue, monthly cash flow, one-time shock, runway, and five lifelines in real time. Industry presets are only editable demo data.
      <break time="12000ms"/>

      Risk Sovereignty avoids the false choice between doing nothing and shutting down. It removes exposure in stages: detect the signal, contain the trend, isolate contagion, and stop the bleeding—while keeping each move as reversible as possible.
      <break time="8000ms"/>

      G P T five point six is not allowed to invent financial truth. The server forces a strict function call to the stress-test engine. The submitted case is preserved, calculated locally, and returned to the model. A second G P T five point six pass must produce a strict structured report: the causal chain, exactly three staged actions, critical assumptions, and one question the owner cannot avoid.
      <break time="17000ms"/>

      Every action cites calculation or assumption evidence. The interface keeps four boundaries visible: user facts, editable assumptions, deterministic calculations, and A I judgment. That makes the recommendation challengeable instead of merely persuasive. The final audit strip exposes the model name, the forced tool workflow, and both Open A I response I D's as proof of a live run.
      <break time="500ms"/>

      Risk Sovereignty does not predict the future. It controls exposure, preserves exit rights, and helps a small-business owner keep the next move.
    </prosody>
  </voice>
</speak>
