<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<speak version="1.0" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2001/10/synthesis" xml:lang="en-US">
  <voice name="Microsoft Zira Desktop">
    <prosody rate="100%" volume="100">
      Most business A I tells an owner how to grow. Risk Sovereignty asks a harder question: when the world stops cooperating, what breaks first—and which move preserves the right to choose again tomorrow?
      <break time="500ms"/>

      This company appears profitable before stress. But delayed collections, a partial debt call, and inventory impairment consume more cash than it holds. The first failure is cash—not because it is the most dramatic risk, but because it is the weakest constraint.
      <break time="4000ms"/>

      The numbers are not generated by A I. Business facts and stress assumptions stay visible and editable. A deterministic engine recalculates stressed revenue, monthly cash flow, one-time shock, runway, and five lifelines in real time. Industry presets are only editable demo data.
      <break time="12000ms"/>

      Risk Sovereignty avoids the false choice between doing nothing and shutting down. It removes exposure in stages, verifies that the claimed exit actually exists, and preserves resources to participate again. This is not hiding from risk; bounded downside is what makes a bold next move possible.
      <break time="8000ms"/>

      G P T five point six is not allowed to invent financial truth. The server forces a strict function call to the stress-test engine. A second pass must complete the sovereignty gate—exit reality, tolerable loss, re-entry, preserved upside, and decision quality—before producing exactly three staged actions.
      <break time="17000ms"/>

      Every action cites calculation or assumption evidence. A local method audit rejects imaginary evidence or broken phase order. The interface keeps user facts, editable assumptions, deterministic calculations, and A I judgment visibly separate. The final audit strip exposes the model name, methodology version, workflow, and both Open A I response I D's as proof of a live run.
      <break time="500ms"/>

      Risk Sovereignty does not predict the future. It controls exposure, preserves exit rights, and helps a small-business owner keep the next move.
    </prosody>
  </voice>
</speak>
